<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-06T16:06:39+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your Blog Title</title><subtitle>A short description of your blog</subtitle><author><name>Ouaziz</name><email>ouazizmed2@email.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">CVE: An Essential Guide for Cybersecurity Practitioners</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/CVE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CVE: An Essential Guide for Cybersecurity Practitioners" /><published>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/CVE</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/CVE/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-cve&quot;&gt;What is CVE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVE, short for &lt;strong&gt;Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures&lt;/strong&gt;, is a list of publicly disclosed computer security flaws. When someone refers to a CVE, they mean a security flaw that’s been assigned a CVE ID number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVE managed by the &lt;strong&gt;MITRE Corporation&lt;/strong&gt;, a non-profit that operates federally funded research and development centers (FFRDCs), the system provides a reference-method for publicly known information-security vulnerabilities and exposures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-ths-sytem-of-cve-works&quot;&gt;How ths sytem of CVE works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) system works by providing unique identifiers to publicly known cybersecurity vulnerabilities. It operates through a community-driven process managed by the MITRE Corporation, with inputs from cybersecurity researchers, product vendors, and various organizations worldwide. Here’s a simplified explanation of how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover&lt;/strong&gt;: A cybersecurity vulnerability is discovered. This could happen in a variety of ways. For instance, security researchers may discover vulnerabilities during their work, or software vendors might identify them during development or after a product release.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reporting&lt;/strong&gt;: The discovered vulnerability is then reported to MITRE or a CVE Numbering Authority (CNA), which are organizations authorized to assign CVE IDs to vulnerabilities affecting products within their distinct, agreed-upon scope. Large software vendors often act as CNAs for their own products. The reporter provides all necessary details about the vulnerability, such as how it can be exploited, what the impact would be, which versions of software are affected, and whether there are any known mitigations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the reported vulnerability is confirmed, a unique CVE Identifier (CVE ID) is assigned to it. The format of this ID is “CVE-YYYY-NNNNN”, where “YYYY” is the year the ID was assigned, and “NNNNN” is a sequence number with no leading zeros.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;:The ID is reserved, which is the initial state of a CVE Record.
The Reserved state means that CVE stakeholder(s) are using the CVE ID for early-stage vulnerability coordination and management, but the CNA is not yet ready to publicly disclose the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submut&lt;/strong&gt;: CVE Program participant submits the details.
Details include but are not limited to affected product(s); affected or fixed product versions; vulnerability type, root cause, or impact; and at least one public reference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publish&lt;/strong&gt;: The vulnerability details, along with the CVE ID, are then published in the CVE List and made available publicly. The CVE entry includes a brief description of the vulnerability and reference links where more information can be found. This information is also disseminated to various security databases, tools, and services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cve-identifiers&quot;&gt;CVE identifiers&lt;/h1&gt;</content><author><name>Ouaziz</name><email>ouazizmed2@email.com</email></author><summary type="html">What is CVE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/MITRE_ATT&CK/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK" /><published>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/MITRE_ATT&amp;CK</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/MITRE_ATT&amp;CK/">&lt;p&gt;In this post i will talk about MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ouaziz</name><email>ouazizmed2@email.com</email></author><summary type="html">In this post i will talk about MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Datadog Integration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/Datadog_Integration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Datadog Integration" /><published>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/Datadog_Integration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/27/Datadog_Integration/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;datadog&quot;&gt;Datadog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;datadog-agent&quot;&gt;Datadog Agent&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;datadog-integration&quot;&gt;Datadog integration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrations enable you to collect data on specific services using Datadog. You can use Integrations to bring together metrics and logs from your infrastructure and applications into Datadog to gain insight into the unified system as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datadog provides three main types of integrations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agent-based integrations are installed with the Datadog Agent and use a Python class method called check to define the metrics to collect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Authentication (crawler) based integrations are set up in Datadog where you provide credentials for obtaining metrics with the API. These include popular integrations like Slack, AWS, Azure, and PagerDuty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Library integrations use the Datadog API to allow you to monitor applications based on the language they are written in, like Node.js or Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, Datadog’s library of over 400 built-in integrations is sufficient for your use case. However, if you are releasing your own service that you would like to integrate with Datadog or would like a custom integration, you can build your own!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ouaziz</name><email>ouazizmed2@email.com</email></author><summary type="html">Datadog</summary></entry></feed>